{
    "topic": "Data Link Protocol",
    "Subject": "Computer Networks",
    "data": [
        {
            "question": "Which of the following layers of the OSI reference model resolve problems of damaged or lost or duplicate frames ?",
            "op1": "Data link layer",
            "op2": "Network layer",
            "op3": "Session layer",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "X.5 protocol consists of",
            "op1": "Physical and frame levels",
            "op2": "Frame and packet levels",
            "op3": "Physical, frame and packet levels",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "How much channel throughout of slotted ALOHA will be in comparison to pure ALOHA.",
            "op1": "Same",
            "op2": "Double",
            "op3": "Three times",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "X.21 is physical level standard for",
            "op1": "X.25",
            "op2": "CSMA/CD",
            "op3": "ATM networks",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "X.25 LAPP uses a specific subset of",
            "op1": "CSM/CD protocol",
            "op2": "HDLC protocol",
            "op3": "Token ring",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "X.21 protocol consists of",
            "op1": "Physical and frame levels",
            "op2": "Frame and packet levels",
            "op3": "Physical, frame and packet levels",
            "op4": "Only physical level",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "The shortest frame in HDLC protocol is usually the",
            "op1": "Information frame",
            "op2": "Management frame",
            "op3": "Supervisory frame",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Digitization is a combination of sampling and",
            "op1": "Pulse coding",
            "op2": "Shift keying",
            "op3": "Quantization",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following encoding scheme is used by the physical layer of FDDI ?",
            "op1": "3 out of 4",
            "op2": "4 out of 5",
            "op3": "5 out of 6",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If the ________ bit in X.25 standard is set to 1, it means that there is more than one packet.",
            "op1": "Q",
            "op2": "D",
            "op3": "M",
            "op4": "P",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the measure (unit) used to represent signaling rate per second",
            "op1": "Baud",
            "op2": "Hz",
            "op3": "Bps",
            "op4": "None of these",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The device operation at Data Link layer is",
            "op1": "Repeater",
            "op2": "Router",
            "op3": "Bridge",
            "op4": "None of the above",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "In which ARQ, when a NAK is received, all frames sent since the last frame acknowledge are retransmitted",
            "op1": "Go back n",
            "op2": "Stop-and-wait",
            "op3": "Selective Reject",
            "op4": "Both A and B",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Not a function of a data link protocol",
            "op1": "Error control",
            "op2": "Message delineation",
            "op3": "Media access control",
            "op4": "Amplitude shift keying",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "AAl2 is useful for",
            "op1": "Constant bit rate",
            "op2": "Variable bit rate",
            "op3": "onnection oriented packet data",
            "op4": "Connectionless packet data",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following signals is not standard RS-232-C signal ?",
            "op1": "RTS",
            "op2": "CTS",
            "op3": "VDR",
            "op4": "SR",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "An internetworking protocol that provides virtual circuit service across multiple X.25 protocol, is",
            "op1": "X.75",
            "op2": "X.25",
            "op3": "X.21",
            "op4": "X.400",
            "answer:": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following device is used with an X.25 network to provide service to asynchronous terminals",
            "op1": "Gateway",
            "op2": "ridges",
            "op3": "Repeater",
            "op4": "Packet assembler/disassembler",
            "answer:": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following summation operation is performed on the bits to check an error-detecting code ?",
            "op1": "ttenuation",
            "op2": "Codec",
            "op3": "hecksum",
            "op4": "Coder-decoder",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following allows devices on one network to communicate with devices on another network ?",
            "op1": "Modem",
            "op2": "Gateway",
            "op3": "T-switch",
            "op4": "Multiplexer",
            "answer:": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Firewall _____",
            "op1": "Does not allow any connections to the server",
            "op2": "Allows people on the internet to see just one IP address",
            "op3": "Restricts unauthorized users from accessing sensitive data",
            "op4": "Manages password functions.",
            "answer:": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "The maximum data rate that a medium of 10KHz and signal to noise ratio of 30dB is roughly ____",
            "op1": "10K bps",
            "op2": "30K bps",
            "op3": "100K bps",
            "op4": "300K bps",
            "answer:": 4
        }
    ]
}